welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive in this video we're going to be
Kdenlive在这段视频中我们将成为
learning about the copy and paste
了解复制和粘贴
functions and we're going to be playing
函数 我们将会播放
with some basic video and audio effects
具有一些基本的视频和音频效果
so to get started we're gonna grab a
因此 在开始之前 我们将为您带来
video clip if you're following along you
视频剪辑 如果你跟随你
may have downloaded some from like
可能已经从LIKE下载了一些
pixabay or from free sound some audio
Pixabay或从免费声音一些音频
files so we already have a few
文件 所以我们已经有几个
downloaded that we're gonna be using but
下载了我们将要使用的内容 但是
if you don't have some go ahead and grab
如果你没有的话 那就去拿
some from there some nice free video
那里的一些人有一些不错的免费视频
clips you can use we're going to go to
你可以用到的片段 我们要去
my downloads folder I'm going to drag in
我要拖入的下载文件夹
just a few we have this one I'll drag in
只有几个 我们有这个 我来拖进去
this video this is the video of a person
这个视频这是一个人的视频
riding their bike so we'd click play
骑着他们的自行车 这样我们就可以点击播放
it's just bike riding back and forth and
只是骑着自行车来回穿梭
back and forth and maybe we want to
来来回回 也许我们想
create a cool kind of effect where this
创造一种很酷的效果 这是
person like maybe we'll create like this
像这样的人 也许我们会像这样创造
kind of effect where they we want to
一种我们想要的效果
just keep writing like looping back so
继续写下去 就像往回循环一样
we'll we'll drag this video in and we're
我们会我们会把这段视频放进去 我们会
gonna cut it and just copy that portion
我要把它剪下来 然后复制那部分
of the video and play it over and over
一遍又一遍地播放
again maybe four or five times sometimes
再说一次 有时可能是四到五次
just to get its effect in like a music
只是为了让它的效果像音乐一样
video or more or less we're just
视频或或多或少我们只是
learning how to use the copy and paste
学习如何使用复制和粘贴
tool and how to work around our timeline
工具以及如何绕过我们的时间表
so like we always do we first get in I
所以就像我们一直做的那样 我们先上车
like to when I'm working with a short
当我和一位短片一起工作的时候
clip like this I can zoom in a little
像这样的剪辑 我可以放大一点
bit so I can see a little bit more of
这样我就能看到更多一点
that clip and what's going on with it
那段视频和它是怎么回事
one more notch yeah that's good and so
再来一个档次是的 很好 所以
there's no audio with this video clip at
这段视频剪辑没有音频
all but we'll add an audio after so
除了我们之外 我们将在这样之后添加音频
let's just play this and see what it
我们就玩这个 看看会发生什么
looks like so I'm just going to I'm only
看起来我只是要去我只是
gonna use that first part of it if I
我会用它的第一部分 如果我
left click and drag while I'm on this
当我在这个上面时 左键点击并拖动
little white triangle like it's the
小小的白色三角就像它是
playhead I can move around and see frame
我可以四处走动 看到画面
by frame exactly what we're I want to be
通过我们的框架我想成为什么样的人
so maybe I want to end this video when
所以也许我想结束这段视频
he goes out of there so right there I'm
他从那里出来 所以我就在那里
going to click on my razor tool I'll
点击我的剃须刀工具 我将
just click right here on the playhead
只需在播放头上单击此处即可
and then I'll click on my selection tool
然后我会点击我的选择工具
and I'll left click select the rest of
我将点击鼠标左键选择其余的
the video and just hit the Delete key on
视频 只需按Delete键即可
the keyboard now we can zoom in and see
键盘现在我们可以放大并查看
just this
就这件事
little short clip it's if we look at the
一小段短片 如果我们看看
top we can see how long it is it looks
上面我们可以看到它看起来有多长
like it's a little over it's not just
好像一切都结束了 这不仅仅是
one second long see yeah it's about a
一秒钟 再见 是的 这是关于一个
one-second long clip if we want to watch
一秒长的片段如果我们想看的话
this in Reverse by the way on our
顺便说一句 我们的情况正好相反
project monitor we can just hit the
项目监控员 我们可以直接点击
reverse and we'll play the whole thing
倒转 我们将播放整个过程
in Reverse so we can play it and forward
倒退 这样我们就可以向前和向后播放
and play it in Reverse that's sort of
然后倒着放 这有点像
how that works alright so what I want to
它是如何工作的 所以我想要做的是
do I want to find a nice good clip so
我想找一个不错的夹子吗？
I'll left-click and it's kind of scroll
我会左键点击它 它就像是滚动
maybe for this part here about when he's
也许这一部分是关于当他
at this like telephone pole maybe from
在这个像电线杆的地方 可能是从
there so this is where I want to start
这就是我想要开始的地方
I'm gonna I want to cut the clip here
我要--我想把这段剪辑剪下来
first of all so I get my razor tool
首先 我拿到我的剃须刀
again and then I'll cut right there and
再来一次 然后我会从那里切开
you see it kind of snaps it this razor
你看 这把剃须刀有点折断它
tool is kind of moving in like little
工具有点像是在搬进来
increments is not completely fluid and
增量不是完全流动的 而且
that's because we have a not sure where
那是因为我们不确定在哪里
snapping is but we have snapping turned
抓拍是但我们已经把抓拍
on it's an option right here so we have
在这里是一个选项 所以我们有
snap so if we unclick this then we can
快照 所以如果我们取消点击它 我们就可以
kind of go like a lot more granular
有点像是更细粒度的
granularly but with snapping on it makes
颗粒状 但带有折断 使其
it so that we when we hover over our
当我们将鼠标悬停在我们的
playhead for example will cut exactly
例如 PlayHead将精确地
right where I playhead is which is kind
就在我打头的地方 这很好
of nice for us in this case now I want
在这种情况下对我们来说很好 现在我想
to go back to my selection tool I'll
要返回到我的选择工具 我将
drag forward to a couple maybe till he
拖到一对夫妇 也许直到他
gets to this next to pull this next kind
接下来的就是拉下一种
of or sign whatever that is and I'm
或签上任何东西 我就是
going to cut again there so what I've
我要在那里再剪一次 所以我所拥有的
done I've actually cut so now I have
做完了 我真的剪了 所以现在我有
three I've turned this one clip into
三个我把这一段剪辑成了
three clips
三个夹子
well we already shortened it quite a bit
嗯 我们已经把它缩短了不少
and now we have one two three and we can
现在我们有一、二、三 我们可以
use these different video tracks if we
如果我们使用这些不同的视频轨道
want to just to kind of keep things
想要只保留一些东西
clean for us so I'll drag this part up
帮我们清理一下 我把这部分拖上来
to here and maybe this part I'll drag up
到这里 也许我会把这部分拖上来
to this third one I mean I guess I
对于这第三个 我的意思是 我想我
shouldn't say it makes it clean because
不应该说它让它变得干净 因为
it's kind of a matter of preference but
这是一种偏好的问题 但
at least it helps us visually step right
至少它帮助我们在视觉上走对了
out okay we have these three different
好的 我们有这三种不同的
tracks and then if we play this if we
如果我们播放这个曲目 如果我们
play it'll actually play just right
播放它实际上会播放得恰到好处
normally we won't see anything between
正常情况下 我们不会在
we won't see any difference between
我们看不出有什么不同
those I think there's no there's no I
那些我认为没有 没有我
like blinking or anything when it goes
就像它消失时的眨眼之类的东西
from one video clip to the next
从一个视频剪辑到下一个视频剪辑
just seamlessly goes which is pretty
就这样天衣无缝地过去了 这很漂亮
cool all right we want to copy this one
好的 好的 我们想复印这张
so to do that we can do a couple
所以要做到这一点 我们可以做几个
different things we can right-click on
我们可以用鼠标右键点击的不同事物
it and go to copy for one and then we
然后去复印一份然后我们
can just right click and go to paste and
只需右键单击并转到粘贴和
whatever track we right-click and paste
无论我们右击并粘贴的曲目是什么
it in it'll go into that track I think
我想它会进入那个轨道的
we can even put it in an audio track if
我们甚至可以把它放在音频轨道上 如果
we want to
我们想要
yeah it'll go in an audio track I don't
是的 它会放进音轨 我不会
know if you're play in an audio track I
我知道如果你正在播放一首音轨
don't think it will but now I just
我不认为它会 但现在我只是
pasted a whole bunch of these you see so
粘贴了一大堆这样的东西
I'm left clicking around and dragging
我被留下四处点击和拖拽
them all so this is the end part of the
所有这些所以这是最后一部分
video so we want it to be more over here
视频 所以我们希望它更多地在这里
now and then you see it went black
时不时地你会看到它变黑了
because our playhead is sitting right
因为我们的播放头正坐在
here so if we want to see something we
所以如果我们想看点什么 我们
can just remove our playhead over to it
可以把我们的游戏头移到它上面吗？
a certain piece of video and then we'll
一段视频 然后我们将
drag all five it to five yeah we'll drag
把五个都拖到五个是的我们会拖的
all five of these end to end to end to
所有这五个首尾相接的
end and then what that's going to do and
结束 然后它将会做什么
then we'll put this into the end of that
然后我们会把这个放到那个的最后
one and see since we have snap on it
一张 看看 因为我们已经拍到它了
goes perfectly it kind of snaps right to
做得很完美 它就像是在折断
where it's supposed to be and now let's
它应该在哪里 现在让我们
see what this looks like if we hit play
看看如果我们点击Play会是什么样子
so it almost looks like a glitch it's
所以它看起来几乎像是一个小故障
just like going over and over and over
就像一遍又一遍地
again all right
再来一次 好的
that's kind of cool so we did copy where
这很酷 所以我们确实复制了
if we just want to cut though what if we
如果我们只是想要切开 如果我们
wanted to cut maybe we want to start the
想砍掉 也许我们想要开始
video with that with that portion so one
视频和那个部分 所以是一个
thing that is kind of cool if I want to
如果我想的话这是很酷的事情
move maybe we want to move we want to
移动 也许我们想移动 我们想移动
start the this end part of the video we
开始视频的这个结尾部分 我们
want that to be at the beginning and
我希望这是在开始的时候
want the beginning to be at the end but
想要开始是在结束 但
instead of dragging and moving them like
而不是像这样拖拽和移动它们
that we will let's use our cut function
我们将使用我们的Cut函数
so we'll select we'll right-click on the
因此 我们将选择我们将右键单击
the image we want to cut and we go down
我们想要剪切的图像 然后我们就下去了
to we cut the clip what that's gonna do
我们把这段视频剪下来
it stays right there for now but if we
它现在就在那里 但如果我们
want to paste it we right-click I think
想粘贴它 我们右击 我想
it'll go the same let's paste it down
它会一样的 让我们把它贴下来
here right here where this at the
就在这里 在这里 在
playhead I think it'll do that paste so
PlayHead 我想它会这么做的
now it paste it and what did it paste
现在它粘贴了它 它粘贴了什么
oh I thought we have so we want to
哦 我以为我们有 所以我们想
right-click you know what did I cut it
右击你知道我切到什么了吗？
clipped Oh clip
剪裁哦剪裁
project bin so we can send it up to our
项目垃圾箱 这样我们就可以把它发送到我们的
project bin too if we want to but I
如果我们想的话也可以做宾客计划 但是我
don't think it cut it the way I wanted
我不认为这是我想要的方式
it to but that's good to know too so if
我也是 但我也很高兴知道如果
we wanted to send let's say we want to
我们想要发送比方说我们想要
send just this portion of the bike I'm
把自行车的这一部分寄给我
changing my mind now instead of copying
现在改变主意 而不是照搬
this we want to just send it up into our
我们只想把它发送到我们的
project bin we can go clip in project
项目垃圾箱我们可以在项目中进行剪辑
bin and then it clips it right here so
然后它把它夹在这里 所以
in our project monitor it moves this
在我们的项目监视器中 它移动这个
little blue there's this little portion
小蓝 有这一小部分
that's blue now if we drag and drop this
如果我们拖放这个 它现在是蓝色的
actual video in it'll be just that
它里面的实际视频只会是
portion of the video and I didn't really
视频的一部分 我并不是真的
get into that and I'll do that but if we
我会这么做的 但如果我们
want to move this now whatever portion
现在想把这个搬出去吗？不管是什么部分
we drag it'll be that much longer so if
我们拖的时间会更长 所以如果
you don't want to just drag the whole
你不会想把整个
file in you can click and drag just the
文件中的文件 只需单击并拖动
portion that you've clipped in and out
你剪进剪出的那部分
we're getting a little bit into the
我们正在进入一个小范围
weeds here like and I'm not
这里的杂草喜欢而我不是
accomplishing exactly what I'm wanting
完成我想要的东西
to show in this video just yet but let's
在这段视频中展示 但让我们
go ahead and add hopefully I haven't
继续说吧 希望我没有
confused you let's go ahead and add an
迷惑了您 让我们继续添加一个
audio track to this so I'll bring in an
音轨到这个 所以我会带来一个
audio file we don't have any yet this is
我们还没有音频文件 这是
the music we used in our last tutorial
我们在上一个教程中使用的音乐
so we'll collect click and drag it down
所以我们将收集点击并将其拖到下面
and put it right here and then we'll go
把它放在这里 然后我们就走
to the beginning of this and let play
开始吧 让我们一起玩吧
[Music]
[音乐]
she is going really fast because that's
她开得很快 因为那是
where zoomed in so far so we can zoom
放大到现在的位置 这样我们就可以放大
out a little bit and kind of see
出来一点点 然后看一看
differently now our video clips might be
现在不同的是 我们的视频剪辑可能是
harder to click on but at least we can
更难点击 但至少我们可以
see the whole extent of the audio drag
查看音频拖拽的整个范围
let's come here to the last the end and
让我们走到最后 走到尽头
let's cut our audio so we go to our
让我们切断我们的音频 这样我们就可以
razor tool just go down here and
剃须刀工具就在这里
left-click now we have two separate
左键单击 现在我们有两个独立的
audio we'll go back to our selection we
音频我们将返回到我们的选择我们
have an audio track here an audio track
在这里有一个音轨 音轨
here we could move this over here it's
我们可以把这个搬到这里来
gonna sound bad but it's going to be two
听起来很糟糕 但会是两个
different parts of audio playing over
播放音频的不同部分
top of each other
在彼此的顶部
okay let's just keep it it actually kind
好的 让我们就这样吧 实际上是友好的
of goes with our glitchyness so let's
随我们的小插曲而去 所以让我们
come over here to the end of the video
到这里来 到视频的最后
again hit the x key on the keyboard or
再次按键盘上的x键或
click on the razor tool and then left
点击剃须刀工具 然后向左
click to cut hit the S key on the
单击以剪切按下S键
keyboard to go back to selection mode
用于返回选择模式的键盘
and then just delete this last part of
然后删除最后这部分
the audio now I can zoom in here and
现在我可以放大这里的音频
we'll see perfect so this is our video
我们会看到完美的 所以这是我们的视频
clip we see we're using three different
我们看到我们使用了三种不同的
video tracks we don't really need to we
我们真的不需要我们的录像带
have seven total different video clips
总共有七个不同的视频剪辑
that we could actually move around and
我们真的可以四处走动
change let's say maybe we want to have a
让我们说 也许我们想要有一个
little bit of black space in between
中间有一小块黑色空间
each of these we can do that we need to
我们可以做到的每一件事都是我们需要做的
separate this out we can actually drag
把它分开 我们实际上可以拖出来
and put in a little bit of black space
并放入一点黑色空间
between each one of these what that's
在这其中的每一个之间 这是什么
going to do is create this effect of a
要做的就是创建一个
little bit of black in between each one
每一块中间都有一点黑色
so not really in effect and then if we
所以并不是真的有效 如果我们
want we can drag this audio out and this
我们可以把这个音频拖出来 然后这个
is one thing I really wanted to show we
是我真的想向我们展示的一件事
can do this with up with audio clips and
可以使用UP音频剪辑和
video once it's been cut if we scroll to
视频一旦被切断 如果我们滚动到
the end we can actually resize this
最后 我们实际上可以调整它的大小
audio clip now to go to the end of our
音频片段现在转到我们的
video project and it'll just grab the
视频项目 它就会抓住
next part of the audio you see we have
你们看到的音频的下一部分 我们有
this like dip here in audio at the end
这就像是在音频的末尾插入
that's what it sounds like this last one
这最后一个听起来就是这样
we can left-click and we can drag and
我们可以左击 我们可以拖动和
you see it's not actually moving the
你看 它实际上并没有移动
audio it's just getting us more audio so
它只是给我们带来了更多的音频 所以
it's kind of cutting it down to here and
它有点像是把它切到了这里
we can also extend it further again that
我们还可以再延长一次
only works to the extent of the audio
仅在音频范围内有效
file so we can't go we can't we couldn't
所以我们不能去我们不能我们不能
go further past to the end of the audio
再往前走到音频的末尾
file and we couldn't pull it from the
文件 但我们无法将其从
beginning further than the beginning of
从比…开始更远的地方开始
the audio file if that makes sense but
音频文件 如果这有意义的话
the same thing works with a video too so
同样的方法也适用于视频
this ends right here if we look at where
如果我们看一下
this ends it has him going out but we
这结束了他的出局 但我们
since we cut this video clip we could
既然我们剪下了这段视频 我们就可以
left-click and drag and see what's past
左键单击并拖动 查看过去的内容
that part of the video and see what
视频的这一部分 看看是什么
happens so he starts writing in that way
所以他开始用这种方式写作
but we cut that so we could do it the
但我们把它剪掉了 这样我们就可以
way we did we can grab the razor tool
这样我们就能拿到剃须刀工具
and cut it again and delete this part of
再剪一遍 把这部分删掉
the video or if I hit control
视频或者如果我按下控制键
easy to undo that we can actually just
很容易撤销 我们实际上只需
hover to the move our mouse to the end
悬停以将我们的鼠标移动到最后
and left-click and shrink that down a
然后左键单击并将其缩小为
little bit and it accomplishes the same
一点点 它就能达到同样的效果
thing so that's pretty cool then also I
所以这很酷 然后我也
think that's all we're going to do I
我想这就是我们要做的一切
said we're gonna add in this video is
说我们要在这段视频中加上
getting too long so in the next video is
太长了 所以在下一个视频中
when we're going to be doing adding in
当我们要做的是加入
video and audio effects and I'm going to
视频和音频效果 我要
keep all this video up so just join the
继续播放这段视频吧 加入
next tutorial we want to reset up at
下一个教程 我们想要在
anything we'll leave it exactly how it
任何事情 我们都会留下它完全是这样的
is now and we'll just add in some video
我们再加上一些视频
effects so thanks for watching catch you
谢谢收看《抓住你》
in the next video
在下一个视频中